Berkley Olmstead

5531 S. Adonis, Boise, ID 83716 | 208-871-3882 olms2074@gmail.com | www.berklevolmstead.com | github.com/Bolmstead

Summary

Seasoned Senior Full-Stack Software Developer with 3 years experience building SaaS website applications with React, Node, Express, and MongoDB. I am currently leading the development of a SaaS site for Motor Carrier Companies and am building the Frontend, Backend, and API functionality with the MERN stack.

Skills

Languages, Frameworks, and Libraries: Javascript, Typescript, Node.JS, React, Redux, Java, Node Express, SQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Mongoose, MuleSoft Anypoint, JQuery, AWS, HTML, CSS, Less.JS, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Hashing, Encryption, Authorizations, Figma, Ant Design, Material-UI, and Bootstrap.

Other Tools and Skills: Agile Methodology, REST API Development, MongoDB & SQL Database Schema Design, Site Deployment Management, Git, Github, Communicating with External REST and SOAP APIs.

Experience

TEKware - Project: <u>SafetyAuditPrep.com</u> - Remote Position

August 2021 - Present

Senior Full-Stack Software Developer

- Created several React components, backend REST API logic, and MongoDB database architecture for a Motor Carrier Safety Compliance and am currently managing its production site and production database.
- Created entire UI and necessary backend functionality for the site's following features: Promo Codes, Homepage Dashboard, Password Recovery, Task Assignments, Tractor/Trailer Assignments, Register User and Payment Validation, Automated Invoice Creation with Cron Jobs, Drug Test Requests, and others.
- Collaborated with our client, building their requested features and advised on any possible issues.
- Integrated over 5 external REST and SOAP APIs into our code base which include the following: Quest Diagnostics, Google Maps, TazWorks, FMCSA, and Authorize.NET.

Idaho State Tax Commission - Boise, ID

February 2016 - March 2020

Tax Auditor

- Calculated state individual tax deficiencies and prepared audit findings defending my position.
- Handled over 200 audits simultaneously, increasing the state's income by over \$80,000 a year on average.
- Met with taxpayers to communicate tax code ambiguities guiding them to an appropriate plan of action.

Projects

FreeBay Website

February 2021 - Present

- Developed a full-stack product bidding website using React, Node.js, Express, Python, and PostgreSQL.
- Created a UI using CSS and Material UI allowing users to search for products, view users profiles that displays their products won, and a homepage showing the entire site's product bidding activity.
- Built the backend, REST API, and database architecture with Node.JS, Node-PG, and Express.
- Designed and tested API routes that: supply a JWT upon validation, creates and edits users, query product data, inserts bid data, and updates product data when an auction has ended.

Education

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track

Completion Date: April 2021

- 800+ hours of hands-on online course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects.
- Refined skills in front-end and back-end web development, databases, and data structures & algorithms.

University of Idaho- College of Business and Economics - Moscow, ID

B.S. in Business, Accounting and Finance - Cumulative GPA: 3.45

University of Ghana- Accra, Ghana, Africa

Semester Abroad: Spring 2010

Degrees Received: December 2012

Certified Public Accountant Exam - Passed all 4 sections of exam